NABEEL HASAN

New Delhi, India | +91-9634410235 | nabeel.io@outlook.com

Github | Linkedin | Projects

4+ years experience as a Data Analyst and Developer. I am looking forward to applying my skills in the Data Science/ML field. Swift in communication and loves to collaborate. Have experience in data pipeline and structured data analysis

EXPERIENCE

adsify.digital, Data Analyst

NOV 2021 - PRESENT

- Implemented **MySQL** scripts to generate daily reports for orders, finance units, & advertising metrics and analyze data to gather actionable insights and create a set of dashboards using **PowerBI**
- Executed **ETL** pipeline in **AWS EC2** using Python **asyncio & httpx** to asynchronously request multiple reports of sellers and transform raw data into a structured format, resulting in an 80% file size reduction.
- Implemented **Data Warehouse** using **AWS RDS** to gather and store daily reports and KPIs from sellers using Amazon **REST** based **SellingPartner-API** and **Ads API**.

adsify.digital, Python Developer

APR 2020 - OCT 2021

- Implemented a company-wide web application portal using **Flask** and **AWS S3** for managing campaigns, audits, and scraping keywords and deployed using **AWS Beanstalk**.
- Develop a web scraping tool using Beautiful Soup to automatically check the client's sponsored product for a
 given keyword on the listing web page, thereby eliminating the need to verify hundreds of keywords manually
 on the browser.
- Execute development of a **CLI** application in **Python Click, Pandas & Numpy** to automate the process of generating sponsored advertising campaigns for targeted keywords using the Amazon Seller Central portal, resulting in a 90% reduction in campaign generation time without errors.

IHS-Markit Operation Analysis Analyst

AUG 2018 - JAN 2019

- **Predict** the price of illiquid securities using fixed-income data and keep track of price fluctuations.
- Maintaining the health of **yield curves** for GSIBs (Global Systemically Important Banks) and **monitoring** daily market changes.
- Keep the yield curves consistent with market changes using various data cleaning and filtering techniques.

SKILLS

Python, PowerBI, Exploratory Data Analysis, Statistical Analysis, Predictive Modelling, Regression Analysis, Machine Learning, A/B Testing, Web Framework, APIs, MySQL, Data Management, Data Warehousing, Linux, ETL Pipeline and Version Control.

EDUCATION

MBA (Finance) Jamia Millia Islamia

AUG 2016 - APR 2018

Relevant Coursework: Risk Modeling, Financial Markets, Quantitative Analysis, Macro-Economics, Brand Marketing

BSc (Computer Application)

Aligarh Muslim University

AUG 2012 - APR 2015

Relevant Coursework: Programming, Object Oriented Programming, Database Management Systems, Introductory Statistics, and Probability.

CERTIFICATION

Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Google 2023

Database Engineer Professional Certificate, Meta 2023 (Ongoing)